WOMAN: (WHISPERING)
Look, see a world
that holds more wonders than
any since the Earth was born.
And of all who reigned o'er,
none had renown like the boy
who pulled sword from stone.
But this is not that king...
(HOARSELY)
...nor is this his song.
Let me tell you instead
a new tale.
I'll lay it down
as I've heard it told.
Its letters sent,
its history pressed,
of an adventure
brave and bold.
Forever set,
in heart, in stone,
like all great myths of old.
(FLAME ROARING)
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING)
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
(GOAT BLEATING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GOOSE HONKING)
(CHURCH BELL
CONTINUES TOLLING)
(CATTLE LOWING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(DUCK QUACKS)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING
IN DISTANCE)
(DUCKS QUACKING)
(MAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY
IN DISTANCE)
(LUTE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(GASPING)
Christ is born.
(BUCKET CLATTERS)
Christ is born indeed.
(WOMAN LAUGHS)
(MUFFLED LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHTER
AND INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN: Where are
you going?
WOMAN: To church!
MAN: Why?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
My boots.
Hello, Agnes.
Where are my boots?
WOMAN 2:
You a knight yet?
MAN: What?
- Not yet.
- Better hurry up.
MAN: (PANTING)
I've got time.
I've got lots
of time.
Hey! Essel.
- Hey, slow down.
- ESSEL: Hurry up!
MAN: Essel.
Essel.
Let's just stay here. Come on.
Let's just stay here.
- Get up.
- MAN: No.
I'm not ready yet.
(PANTING)
I'm not ready.
Merry Christmas,
Gryngelot.
(CHURCH BELLS TOLLING
IN DISTANCE)
(SOFT WHISTLING)
(CHUCKLES)
(CHURCH BELLS
CONTINUE TOLLING)
- (BELLS TOLLING STOPS)
- (PANTING)
WOMAN: Where have
you been?
GAWAIN: At Mass.
- WOMAN: You, at Mass?
- GAWAIN: Yeah.
WOMAN: All night?
Yes.
WOMAN: Well,
where are your boots?
GAWAIN: What?
- WOMAN: Where are...
- (KISSES)
You do smell like
you've been at Mass.
What, have you been drinking
the sacrament all night?
GAWAIN:
I love you, Mother.
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHING)
(GENTLE STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
You are not dressed.
I've got no guts
for merriment this year.
But it's Christmas.
MOTHER: There'll be
more Christmases,
more feasts,
more glad tidings.
You go,
make merry.
And tell me
what you see.
(FESTIVE STRING
MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMAN SINGING
IN MEDIEVAL LANGUAGE)
(DOOR OPENING)
(WOMAN CONTINUES SINGING)
(SONG ENDS)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(PENSIVE CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(PENSIVE CHORAL MUSIC
CONTINUES)
(MUFFLED LAUGHTER)
Bring young
Gawain here.
(SOFTLY) The king
would speak with you.
(LIGHT MEDIEVAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
Where is thy mother?
She was not feeling
herself, my lord.
Then come. Sit here, besides us.
Besides me
and my queen.
That is not
my place.
No. Let it
be, today.
Its owner
is away.
Who knows when
he will return?
Please.
Good to see
you, Gawain.
Good to have one's
family by one's side.
One's blood.
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
Surely your
knights have
spilled enough blood
in your name
to bind them closer
to you than I.
KING: True.
But you are
my sister's boy,
queefed from
her womb.
They are not.
I look out upon my friends
here today and I see...
songs...
no muse could ever
sing or dream of.
But I turn to thee
and I see what?
I recognize but I
do not know thee.
I say this not in
reproach, but regret
that I have never asked
you to sit at my side
before this day
or upon my knee when
thy was newborn.
But now
it is Christmas,
and I wish
to build bridges.
So before
we make merry...
you make
for me a gift.
You tell me a tale of yourself,
so that I might
know thee.
(SOFT STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
I have none to tell, King.
QUEEN: Yet.
You have none
to tell yet.
GAWAIN: Yet.
Look around you,
young Gawain.
What do you see?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
I see legends.
Do not take your place
amongst them idly.
KING: Hmm.
So who else then...
hmm?
Friends...
Brothers...
(SOFTLY) Brothers...
Brothers and...
- sisters all.
- ...sisters all.
I thank thee
for breaking bread with
me this blessed day.
And it is blessed...
for out my window
this morn I looked,
and I saw a land
shaped...
by your hands.
(DRAMATIC CHORAL MUSIC PLAYS)
You have lain those same
hands upon our Saxon brethren,
who now in your shadow
bow their heads
like babes.
Peace, peace you have
brought to your kingdom,
so it is in peace
that I...
I now say to you...
I am the luckiest
here today...
because I am
amongst thee.
I am amongst thee.
So before
we celebrate
the birth
of our Christ,
let us honor
one of our own
who has done great
things in His name.
So a tale, or...
- Or a show perhaps.
- (THUNDER CRASHES)
What have thee?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Who can regale me
and my queen
with some myth
or canto
of thine
own purport?
(WIND WHISTLING)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS)
Hold.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(HORSE GRUNTS)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
DISTORTED MALE VOICE:
Oh, Greatest Of Kings,
indulge me in this friendly
Christmas game.
Let whichever
of your knights
is boldest of blood
and wildest of heart
step forth,
take up arms,
and try with honor
to land a blow against me.
Whomsoever nicks me
shall lay claim
to this, my arm.
It's glory and riches
shall be thine.
But...
thy champ must bind
himself to this:
Should he land
a blow,
then one year
and Yuletide hence,
he must seek me
out yonder,
to the Green Chapel
six nights to the North.
He shall find me there
and bend the knee
and let me strike him
in return.
Be it a scratch on the cheek
or a cut on the throat,
I will return
what was given to me,
and then in trust
and friendship we shall part.
Who, then,
who is willing to engage with me?
(ALL EXCLAIM)
Help. Queen.
(HORSE SNORTING)
This challenge
is thine own?
(RUSTLING)
Though my will longs
to leap across this
table and meet thee,
my body will
not follow.
Surely there is one
amongst us here
who will meet this
knight on his terms.
GAWAIN: I will do it.
I will meet him.
I will meet thee.
You understand
this challenge?
GAWAIN: I do.
I think I do.
(WHISPERS) Remember,
it is only a game.
(RUSTLING)
I need a sword.
I need...
KING: Gawain.
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
(RUSTLING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Have at me,
Green Knight.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Make a move
or I shall make mine.
(SCOFFS)
What is this?
A trick?
Stand up
and face me!
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
What do you
expect me to do?
(WHISPERING)
Have courage.
(RUSTLING)
Very well.
You laid down
your challenge.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
I accepted it and
I accept it still.
Never forget
what happened here
upon this
Christmas Day!
(GRUNTS)
(SOFT UNSETTLING
MUSIC PLAYING)
(RUSTLING)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
(SLOW DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
One year hence...
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING
MANIACALLY)
(NEIGHING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING
MANIACALLY)
(SLOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHEERING)
(SLOW TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MUSIC ENDS IN FLOURISH)
(CROWD LAUGHING)
(CHILDREN GASPING)
(SOFT EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
ESSEL: What did it
feel like?
What did it feel
like when you...
Like cutting
a melon in two.
And what does
that feel like?
GAWAIN: Like nothing.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Were you afraid?
No.
Are you just
saying that?
GAWAIN: I am here,
and he is not.
(WHEEL RATTLING)
The king lent
me his sword,
did you know that?
You held it?
Well, I did more
than hold it.
(ESSEL LAUGHING)
Behold, Brave
Sir Gawain,
- chopper of heads...
- (CHUCKLES)
...severer of melons,
who cannot...
(WHISPERS)
...get it up.
(CHUCKLES)
(PENSIVE STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
- (MUG THUDS)
- (LAUGHING)
(MEDIEVAL MUSIC PLAYING)
You're Gawain,
aren't you?
Nah, you must
be mistaken.
No, no,
you're him.
You're always here.
Always about.
Scarcely leave
upright most nights.
But not
on Christmas.
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- Have you heard?
This boy slew
the Green Knight.
With his own axe,
he lopped off
the giant's head,
and now he
drinks with us!
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN: But his
mother's a witch.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(CROWD LAUGHING
AND EXCLAIMING)
AND CHATTERING)
(LAUGHTER AND CHATTER SUBSIDE)
(SIGHS)
Rise.
(STERNLY) Rise.
Sit.
I've been
waiting for you.
Did you not
hear me calling?
(KING GRUNTS)
(SOFT CRUNCH)
(GRUNTS IN PAIN)
My tooth hurts.
Another year
nearly gone already.
Have you thought
what you will do
when Christmas comes?
Was it not just a game?
Perhaps.
But it is
not complete.
You truly believe
he's sitting in a chapel,
counting the hours,
whiling away the year
waiting for me to come?
Well, I do not know.
You will tell me.
You must seek him out.
And if death awaits me?
Oh, I do not know
of any man
who has not marched up to
greet death before his time.
Why are you holding me
to this light?
Is it wrong to want
greatness for you?
I fear I am not meant
for greatness.
Mm.
(WATER TRICKLES)
(SOFT STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
You have mud
on your face.
(SOFT STRING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(WHEEL RATTLING)
(LIGHT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOMBER STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHORUS SINGING)
(WOMEN CHANTING INDISTINCTLY)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(PRIEST PRAYING IN LATIN)
(PRIEST CONTINUES PRAYING)
QUEEN: (IN ENGLISH)
May the Blessed Virgin
keep your five
fingers strong,
your five senses sharp.
May her five joys
inspire you.
The five wounds of her
son give you fervor.
And the five virtues
of a knight light your way.
Keep thy covenant,
young Gawain.
And if God smiles on thee,
then hurry thee back.
Thy seat besides us waits.
(BLOWS SOFTLY)
ESSEL: Are you really
going to go?
Should I?
I like your head better
where it is.
GAWAIN: I gave my word.
I made a covenant.
This is how
silly men perish.
GAWAIN: Or how brave
men become great.
ESSEL: Why greatness?
Why is goodness
not enough?
(ETHEREAL CHORAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
MOTHER: Take this now.
Wear it about your
waist as you go.
And if you wear it
still when you return...
Will I return?
When you return,
you will come with
your head held high.
I promise, you will
not come to harm.
And, boy...
My boy...
do not waste this.
(MUSIC ENDS IN FLOURISH)
KID: Gawain!
Gawain!
I've got a sword!
KID 2: Gawain!
Great tide.
Good luck!
Good luck,
Gawain!
(SHEEP BLEATING)
(SHEPHERD SHOUTING
COMMANDS)
(JINGLING)
ESSEL: Do you
still fancy me?
Do I make you happy?
GAWAIN: Yes.
ESSEL: Even though I'm
here and you're there?
GAWAIN: Yes.
(TREE THUDS)
ESSEL: What will you say if I
asked you to make me your lady?
- A lady?
- Your lady.
I could give you more
gold than any lady has.
(SCOFFS) I already
have your gold.
What if I wanted to
sit by your side and...
take your
hand and...
have your ear?
What will you
say to that?
"Why, yes, Essel.
"I'd like that
very much.
"You may have my ear
and my hand and heart.
"And I will be king
and you my queen.
"You'll be
my lady...
"and I'll be
your man."
(THUNDER RUMBLES DISTANTLY)
(JINGLING)
(CAGE CREAKING)
(INSECTS CHIRPING SOFTLY)
(HORSE GALLOPING)
(HORSE SNORTING)
(SOMBER STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND GUSTING)
(BIRDS CAWING IN DISTANCE)
Who are you?
Just a traveler,
friend.
You look like
a knight.
Just passing through.
Ah. I take it you'll want
some of the shares, so, huh?
Of what?
All of this!
Why weren't
they buried?
All dead.
No one
to bury 'em.
Though you know,
nature will do its trick.
She'll suck 'em in
and tuck 'em tight.
(GRUNTS)
Eh, in saying that,
I do have two brothers
out here somewhere.
And they marched off.
They never came home.
You know,
if it weren't for my ma,
I would've been here.
I would've been here!
I would've been
here too!
(BIRD CAWING DISTANTLY)
They all came
here! (LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
Though I'd have
lasted longer.
The king,
they say...
They say the king,
he killed 960
all on his lonesome.
- Nine hundred, eh?
- Uh-huh.
Now, if it was me,
I'da stayed upright long
enough to take my shot.
(EXCLAIMS)
That's a nice
axe you got.
You do some fighting
with that axe?
- Here and there.
- Here?
Only there.
Here, I'm just
passing through.
SCAVENGER:
To where?
GAWAIN: I go North.
North, oh!
North is a direction, all right.
Just North?
To the Green Chapel.
(GASPS)
Oh!
Do you know of it?
The Green Chapel, eh?
There's a stream
yonder.
It runs Northlike.
I mean, if I've...
If I've got my bearing.
Yeah, yeah,
it runs Northlike.
But if you follow that
for a day and a half,
you'll come
to a chapel.
At least I think
it's a chapel.
It's, uh... It's,
uh, yeah, it's...
It's not green
on the whole,
but I mean, it's
definitely greenish,
with the moss and the, uh...
the rot and ruins,
but perhaps it's
what you seek.
GAWAIN: The stream
is yonder?
SCAVENGER:
Mmm-hmm.
It's this way.
Past the field,
where the forest meets.
GAWAIN: I will seek it out.
My thanks to you.
SCAVENGER:
GAWAIN:
Come on.
SCAVENGER: Are my directions
not worth anything to you?
GAWAIN:
My thanks.
I said, are my directions
not worth anything to you?
(SOFT EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
I mean, a knight like you
could spare a wretch like me
just a small,
small act of kindness.
(METALLIC JINGLING)
Here. A kindness.
Oh!
Wait.
(BLOWS)
Northlike. See?
Thank you.
Remember the stream.
GAWAIN: I will.
'Cause it gets tricky.
Here you go, boy.
That's a good boy.
Good boy.
(HORSE NICKERS)
Come on. Let's go.
(ANIMAL HOWLING IN DISTANCE)
Hello, there.
Hello.
(HORSE SNORTING)
Now, now.
- (HORSE WHINNIES)
- (GRUNTS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
- Please.
- THIEF 1: Yeah, please?
- Please. Please. Please!
- THIEF 2: Please!
- THIEF 1: Please.
(GRUNTING)
(MOCKINGLY) Please!
Please! Please! Please!
THIEF 1: Please.
(GAWAIN PANTING)
SCAVENGER: Oh.
Oh.
'Tweren't enough.
Just 'tweren't enough.
(GAWAIN GRUNTING)
Hey, hey, hey!
Where you off to, huh?
Where you off to?
A knightly quest?
I'm not a knight.
(PANTING)
But you said
you were.
I never said that.
You said that.
I never said
I was a knight.
- But are you?
- No! No, I'm not.
Oh.
Hmm.
- Well, you look like one.
- THIEF 1: Aye.
(SNIFFS) Smells like a knight.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHUSHING)
- Oh...
- Please...
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Oh. Oh!
- (BLADE SWISHES)
- Ah.
Whoa!
Whoo!
- Yeah! (LAUGHS)
- (THIEVES LAUGH)
Just tell me, then.
Is there really a chapel?
You're in it.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS)
(SCREAMS)
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
(CONTINUES SHOUTING)
SCAVENGER: Whoa!
Watch it.
THIEF 3: Let me
hold that.
(YELPS)
SCAVENGER:
It suits me.
This suits
me, huh?
(MUFFLED GRUNT)
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
You rest your bones,
my brave little knight.
(GRUNTS)
I'll finish your
quest for you.
I'll finish it good.
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(GRUNTING)
THIEF 3: Hey!
Where are you going?
- Hey!
- SCAVENGER: Hyah!
(TREES RUSTLING)
(BIRD CAWING IN DISTANCE)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(BIRD CAWING DISTANTLY)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(LOW UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRD CAWING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(BIRD CALLING)
(MUSIC INTENSIFYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(PERCUSSION MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTING)
(CHORUS SINGING)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(PERCUSSION MUSIC CONTINUES)
Gryngelot!
(CHORUS SINGING)
(PANTING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- (DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY)
(SOFT CREAKING)
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
(CREAKING)
Hello.
(GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES)
WOMAN: What are you
doing in my bed?
What are you doing
in my bed?
I'm very sorry.
I... I did not see you.
I thought there
was no one about.
I did not mean
to offend thee.
Wait.
Did my father
send for you?
No. He did not.
I do not know
your father.
I am just a lost traveler,
seeking rest for the night,
but I will
leave forthwith.
Where are you going?
Home.
I'm headed home.
And you've lost
your way?
Yes.
I've lost something
as well.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS)
Will you
help me find it?
What are you doing?
- I was just...
- Do not touch me.
A knight should
know better.
(MELLOW STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
GAWAIN: What is your
name, my lady?
I'm called
Winifred.
You heard of me?
GAWAIN: No.
There.
GAWAIN: What is it
I'm looking for?
WINIFRED:
My head.
GAWAIN: Your head is on your
neck, my lady.
No. It is not.
It might look like it
is, but it is not.
It is in the spring.
Well, how did it happen
to get there?
WINIFRED: A lord came seeking
shelter, like thee.
Perhaps
he was thee.
- Was he?
- GAWAIN: No.
WINIFRED:
You certain?
GAWAIN: Yes.
WINIFRED: This lord
sought to lay with me.
I fought him off,
but he returned in the night
and broke down
my door.
I tried to flee,
but he cut off my head.
He threw it in the spring,
and now, try as I might,
I cannot get at it.
My lady...
My lady.
Are you real,
or are you a spirit?
What is the difference?
I just need my head.
As will I before
the year is out.
(SOMBER STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
If I go in there
and find it,
what would you offer
me in exchange?
Why would you
ask me that?
Why would you ever
(SOFT CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS)
(SOMBER CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING)
WINIFRED AND KING: Gawain...
(SOMBER CHORAL MUSIC
CONTINUES)
(GASPING)
(PANTING)
My lady.
(SOFT STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(WHISPERING)
Now I can see thee.
And I will strike
thee down
with every care
I have for thee.
The Green Knight
is someone you know.
(LIGHT CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(DARK ORCHESTRAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (GAWAIN GRUNTING)
- (STONES STRIKING)
(SHIVERING)
(BLOWS)
(GRUNTS)
(FOX GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Well, come on in
if you want.
(GENTLE STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFLES)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(JINGLING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(CHUCKLES)
(SHIVERING)
(SNIFFS)
(FOX WHINING)
(SNIFFLES)
(GRUNTS, PANTING)
(GAGS)
(VOMITS)
(COUGHING)
(PANTING HEAVILY)
(GASPING)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(GENTLE ORCHESTRAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
- (SOPRANO SINGING)
- (THUNDER CONTINUES CRASHING)
(RUSTLING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(SOPRANO CONTINUES SINGING)
(HEAVY THUD)
(EARTH CRUMBLING)
(HEAVY FOOTFALLS)
(SOPRANO CONTINUES SINGING)
(PANTING)
(ECHOING) Hey! Hey!
Which direction
are you headed?
Might a weary traverse the
valley on your shoulder?
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(FOX GROWLING)
(HOWLING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(VOCALIZING IN HIGH-PITCH)
(VOICES VOCALIZING)
(VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(RATTLING)
(VOCALIZING CONTINUES
DISTANTLY)
(THUNDER CRASHES)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GENTLE STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER CONTINUES RUMBLING)
(FOX GRUNTS)
(GENTLE STRING
MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CHORUS SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
MAN: Friend!
Welcome!
(GROANS)
(WOMAN HUMMING SOFTLY)
(MAN SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
- (GASPING)
- Easy now, easy.
- Who are you?
- Have no fear.
- You're among friends.
- Where are my clothes?
Shh. Easy.
Wha...
What day is it?
It is December
the 21st.
Oh, fear not,
Sir Gawain.
You've only slept
through the night.
How do you
know my name?
I know more
than just your name.
You must eat.
See, upon the new year,
I travel to the West.
Came you one week hence and
an empty home greet you.
Till then, though,
I will hunt.
I will hunt,
you shall rest
and we shall both be
all the better for it.
Ah.
And here is our friend, my lady,
fresh from
his slumbers.
(ENCHANTING STRING
MUSIC PLAYING)
(KISSES)
(GRUNTS)
And here, friend,
is your
breakfast
to replenish
your strength.
Surely, you
will need it.
- GAWAIN: Why is that?
- (LADY CHUCKLES)
Because you are
brave, Sir Gawain,
come to face
the Green Knight.
I dare say every
table in this land
has heard of you
and sung your song.
Sir Gawain, the finest
and most virtuous knight,
seeking his destiny
across these lands.
GAWAIN: Perhaps you think
that I am something I'm not.
Such as what?
(CHUCKLES)
How long will you stay with us?
I must make my
appointment by Christmas.
I will eat and give thanks
and then take my leave.
LORD: Nonsense.
Don't you know?
The Green Chapel
is not far.
GAWAIN: Do you
know of it?
LORD: You are
very nearly there.
It's down the river,
not one day's journey.
Are you certain
it is that close?
You are at the end
of your quest, Gawain.
A little sooner than
you expected, perhaps.
But such is the case for us all.
Here is what
will happen.
On Christmas morn,
we will send you on your way.
And by nightfall,
you will be at the
doorway of your destiny.
So stay
a while. Rest.
And make
yourself content.
- (HORSES GALLOPING DISTANTLY)
- (DOGS BARKING)
(OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
LADY: What did
you find?
I never knew so many
books even existed.
Have you...
Have you read them all?
Yes.
All of them
I've read.
Some I've written,
some I've copied.
They're tales
I've heard,
songs that have
been sung to me.
I write them down
and sometimes...
Don't tell
anyone this.
Sometimes when I see
room for improvements...
I make them.
- Do you like books?
- Yes.
Well...
Why don't you take
one with you?
GAWAIN:
I couldn't.
Oh, but it is
nearly Christmas.
Here.
This one's for you.
I thank you.
Should not a knight offer
a lady a kiss in thanks?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Will you sit for me?
Sit for you?
For a portrait.
Ah. I've had my
portrait made already.
Not by me.
(SOMBER STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
GAWAIN: "Ant love
is to myn herte gon
"With one spere so kene..."
Hold very still.
GAWAIN: "Nyht ant day
my blod hit drynkes
"Myn herte deth me tene."
(SOMBER STRING
MUSIC CONTINUES)
That's a very
queer painting.
What's that?
GAWAIN: What?
This.
It's a token.
For what?
For good luck?
For love?
No.
LADY: Surely a knight
knows something of love.
I don't.
Truly?
(JINGLING)
(OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
LORD: Gawain!
Look what I have
brought you!
(LAUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
When I dispersed of him,
I thought what a gift!
What a gift
for my new friend.
What shall
I do with it?
Well, take it with you
for your journey.
I thought you said
it was not far.
I mean your journey
home, after.
Let us make a promise
to each other.
I hunt tomorrow
and the day after.
Whatever the forest
offers me,
I will bring you
home the best.
And you
give me in turn
whatever you might
receive here.
What might I receive here
that is not already yours?
Who knows?
This house is full
of strange things.
But then again,
I see things everywhere
that bear no logic.
Have you ever seen
a hawk kill a horse?
Just swoop
down and...
Phew. It's terrible.
Every man should see
it at least once.
But that is the world.
And the world is fit
for all manner of mysteries.
A man's home, though,
should be safe from all that.
One wall joined
with another,
line and plumb.
Good, strong walls,
and a fire within.
Why is he green,
do you think?
The knight?
Yes.
Was he born
that way?
Perhaps it is the color of
his blood when he blushes.
But why green?
Why not blue
or red?
Because he is not
of this earth.
LADY: But green
is the color of earth,
of living things,
of life.
- And of rot.
- Yes.
Yes.
(LADY CHUCKLES
SOFTLY)
We deck our halls with
it and dye our linens.
But should it come
creeping up the cobbles,
we scrub it out,
fast as we can.
When it blooms beneath our
skin, we bleed it out.
And when we,
together all,
find that our reach
has exceeded our grasp,
we cut it down,
we stamp it out,
we spread ourselves atop it
and smother it
beneath our bellies,
but it comes back.
It does not dally,
nor does it wait to
plot or conspire.
Pull it out by
the roots one day
and then next,
there it is,
creeping in around
the edges.
Whilst we're off
looking for red,
in comes green.
Red is the color
of lust,
but green is what
lust leaves behind,
in heart,
in womb.
Green is what is left
when ardor fades,
when passion dies,
when we die, too.
(BIRDS CHIRPING DISTANTLY)
When you go,
your footprints will fill with grass.
Moss shall cover
your tombstone,
and as
the sun rises,
green shall
spread over all,
in all its shades
and hues.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
This verdigris will
overtake your swords
and your coins
and your battlements
and, try as
you might,
all you hold dear
will succumb to it.
Your skin,
your bones.
Your virtue.
(WIND WHISTLING)
And what do you
hope to gain
from facing
all of this...
this hue?
Honor?
Are you asking me?
- No.
- Hmm.
Honor.
That is why a knight
does what he does.
And this is what
you want most in life?
To be a knight.
No, honor.
(CHUCKLING) You are not
very good with questions.
(SCOFFS)
It is part of
the life I want.
And this is all it takes
for that part to be had?
You'll do this one thing,
you return home
a changed man,
an honorable man?
Just like that?
Yes.
Hmm.
(SIGHING) Oh, I wish
I could see the new you.
But perhaps we will
miss our old friend
and our fun and our games.
(CHUCKLES)
(GENTLE STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS)
(ETHEREAL CHORAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(HORSES GALLOPING FAINTLY)
- My lady...
- Shh.
Why did you not come
to my chambers yesterday?
GAWAIN: I couldn't.
You couldn't?
No, but...
But you wanted to.
Yes.
And now?
I would that
I could, but...
- But...
- It isn't right.
LADY: Hmm.
Isn't right.
No.
(WHISPERS) Do you
believe in magic?
What?
In witchcraft.
Do you believe in it?
Yes. I do.
It is all around us.
I have a gift
for you.
(GAWAIN BREATHES
SHAKILY)
Where did you
get that?
I made it.
(GAWAIN BREATHES
HEAVILY)
There's an enchantment
sewn into its threads.
Wear it and you will
never be struck down.
By what?
By man, or spirit,
or any other implements.
I promise,
you will not
come to harm...
as long as it is
about your waist.
Do you mean it?
- Yes.
- (BREATHING SHAKILY)
You want it? Huh.
Do you want it?
Yes.
Then tell me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
It's okay, tell me.
I want it.
Good.
(GAWAIN PANTING)
Then take it.
Go on, take it.
Take it.
(GAWAIN GRUNTS)
(GAWAIN PANTING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
You are no knight.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
LORD: Gawain!
Where are you going?
I must make
my appointment.
LORD: Oh, on your
own, after all?
What of our game?
I don't want your games,
or your gifts, or your kindness.
Are you certain there is
nothing you wish to give me?
(SIGHS)
There is something.
And I think I can
take it from you.
Unhand me
and let us
go our ways.
Very well.
Gawain!
I... (CHUCKLES)
I caught this poor fellow
in a trap this morning.
I was going
to give him to you,
but I suppose we should
leave him to nature.
(LORD GRUNTS)
Farewell,
Sir Gawain.
And happy Christmas!
If you come back by this way
again, we shall be gone!
(FOX GRUNTS)
(FOX GROWLING)
(SNARLING)
- Why do you stop me?
- (SNARLS)
I cannot tarry.
FOX: Go that way and
your doom is at hand.
You will find no mercy.
No happy end.
What witchcraft
is this?
No witchcraft.
He you seek
is as wild as I,
but knows no measure.
I know what I face.
If any man truly knew,
he would bear his shame
happily and turn away,
head held high,
to end his song as he saw fit.
His secret would
be safe with me.
Are you this man?
No.
The spell about your
waist says otherwise.
This is just
a dirty rag.
FOX: Leave it
here, then.
GAWAIN: It was a gift.
No need for gifts
where you are headed.
Come, come home.
Come home with me.
(GAWAIN GRUNTS)
I never asked for
your company anyway!
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(DRAMATIC CHORAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
(SOFT THUD)
(LOUD HEARTBEAT)
(HEARTBEAT SLOWING)
(HEARTBEAT FADES)
- (WIND BLOWING)
- (LEAVES RUSTLING)
(WATER FLOWING NEARBY)
(WOOD CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(WOOD CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
You came.
Good sir,
is it Christmas?
Yes.
(WOOD CREAKING)
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS)
(BIRDS FLUTTERING AWAY)
Do you recall
where you cut me?
I do.
And have you come to see
that blow returned?
I have.
Then kneel,
and we shall complete
our game.
Now?
Aye.
Now, one strike
as good as you gave.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Sir, you flinch.
(PANTING) I know.
I know. (SNIFFLES)
Did I show
signs of fear
when our positions
were reversed?
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
I'm not so confident
as thee.
You have had a year
to find courage.
One year or a hundred,
it wouldn't make a difference.
(SNIFFLES, GRUNTS)
Give me a moment.
(PANTING)
(RAPID HEARTBEAT)
Are you ready?
(HEARTBEAT QUICKENING)
Yes.
Then I shall
get to hacking.
Wait! Wait. (GASPING)
Is this... (PANTING)
...really all
there is?
Is that...
Is this...
What else ought there be?
(DARK CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(YELPS) No! No.
I'm sorry.
I cannot.
(ORCHESTRAL FOLK
MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMAN SINGING
IN MEDIEVAL LANGUAGE)
(GAWAIN GASPING)
(HORSE GRUNTING SOFTLY)
(GENTLE FOLK MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: ♪ Bloom, bloom
Sweet lily flower
♪ The brown bird
Sings its melody
♪ Bloom, bloom
Sweet lily flower
♪ I go to see Saint Mary
♪ Hold, hold my hand in yours
♪ Hold, hold my hand
♪ Cold, cold the night
Has grown
♪ No coin to pay the fare
MOTHER: Shh.
(GENTLE FOLK
MUSIC CONTINUES)
MAN: ♪ Hold, hold my hand
Dear love
♪ Hold, hold my hand
♪ Cold, cold the night
Has grown
♪ No coin to ease my want
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪ Bloom, bloom
Sweet lily flower
♪ The brown bird
Trills its melody
♪ Bloom, bloom
Sweet lily flower
♪ I go to see Saint Mary ♪
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(PANTS)
(KING GRUNTS)
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
(SOFT STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(KING GROANS)
(SOFT STRING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(KING GRUNTS WEAKLY)
(KING GRUNTS)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(FEMALE SINGER SINGING
IN MEDIEVAL LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
♪ Sing thy song, ole, ole, ole
(WOMAN CRYING)
FEMALE SINGER:
♪ Now the child he come
(CRYING IN PAIN)
(WAILS)
(GASPING AND GROANING)
(FEMALE SINGER
CONTINUES SINGING)
♪ Ye lie in joy and wickedness
(FEMALE SINGER SINGS
IN MEDIEVAL LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
♪ Sing thy song, ole, ole, ole
♪ Sing thy song
Ole, ole, ole ♪
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
(BABY GURGLING)
(BABY CRYING)
(ESSEL CRYING)
(ESSEL AND BABY
CONTINUE CRYING)
(CONTINUES CRYING)
(WAILING)
(HEAVENLY CHORAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(ENCHANTING STRING
(HEAVENLY CHORAL
MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CRACKS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(CLATTERING)
(RUMBLING AND EXPLOSIONS)
(BOY GASPING)
(GAWAIN BREATHES SHAKILY)
(WINCES)
(BOY GASPS SOFTLY)
(PENSIVE CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD JEERING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(SWORD UNSHEATHES)
- (SWORD SWISHES)
- (MAN GROANS)
(SOMBER STRING MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE MURMURING)
(SOMBER STRING
MUSIC CONTINUES)
(YOUNG QUEEN HUMMING)
- (CONTINUES HUMMING)
- (FIRE ROARING IN DISTANCE)
(SWORDS CLASHING IN DISTANCE)
(MEN SHOUTING DISTANTLY)
(FLAME ROARING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(DISTANT CLAMORING)
(HEAVY THUD)
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
(THUDDING)
(DOOR THUDS)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(DOOR CONTINUES THUDDING)
(MUSIC RISING)
(MUSIC ENDS IN FLOURISH)
(SIGHS)
(EERIE CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(SQUELCHING)
(GASPING SOFTLY)
(SOFT RUSTLING)
(MUSIC FADES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Wait.
Wait. (BREATHING HEAVILY)
There. Now I'm ready.
I'm ready now.
Well done,
my brave knight.
Now...
Off with your head.
(BELL DINGS)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(GENTLE MEDIEVAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: (SINGING)
♪ Be merry, sweet Lord
♪ On this yules day
♪ A briar come with me and fly
♪ Be merry, sweet Lord
On giving me thine gift
♪ I swear that I'm free now
With rubies so swift
♪ Be merry, sweet Lord
And beg pardon me
♪ Pleasure and treasure
And soft melody
♪ Be merry, sweet Lord
Thank God thousand time
♪ Feast up and go now
And be the sweet cream
♪ Be merry, sweet Lord
Me sweet achen licht
(SINGING IN MEDIEVAL LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) ♪ Be merry,
sweet Lord On this yules day
(SINGING IN MEDIEVAL LANGUAGE)
(SONG ENDS)
(GENTLE ORCHESTRAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOPRANO SINGING)
(SONG ENDS)
(DARK ORCHESTRAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHORUS HARMONIZING)
(MUSIC ENDS)
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull